=Godslayer=
(Adapted from the novel Godslayer.)
(Divine Era, Lunisolar Calendar,
Ninth Night)
The Ascension Jade Disc
has two faces: god and monster.
(Lower City Arena)
The toss decides who chooses the arena.
If it lands on the monster face,
(Lower City Arena)
the Challenger chooses the arena.
If it lands on the god face,
the Defender chooses.
The Lower City has three arenas,
each with two aspects,
embodying six forces:
Thunder, Wind, Water, Fire, Mountain,
and Marsh.
Each has its strengths,
and each has its counter.
(Challenger)
(Thunder is born from the clouds.)
(Mountain blocks the path of wind
and cloud.)
(Without flowing clouds,)
(thunder cannot rise.)
(If we get the Mountain field,)
(we can counter Thunder.)
(Defender)
(As long as we get the Thunder field,)
(they're as good as dead.)
(Everything's been taken care of.)
(It'll land on the god face.)
What are you doing?
(Defender)
He's trying to cheat!
We can't let him choose the arena!
What's that supposed to mean?
No need to look.
You choose.
I choose Thunder!
Whelp,
in a Thunder arena,
heavenly thunder
is amplified severalfold.
You're dead.
You're scared?
Nonsense!
If you're not scared,
why choose Thunder?
I chose Thunder
to make your death even more miserable.
The one who should be scared
is you!
Chicken out and you're my son.
No, my grandson.
(Qi Family)
Dad.
That strike he used to kill Heyu
had at least twenty years of cultivation
behind it.
Can I withstand that?
You have to, whether you can or not.
Tomorrow's fight
is about the honor of our sect.
(Qi Hao's Father)
You must win.
Losing is not an option.
But, Dad...
If I lose,
I'll die.
Sometimes,
a fight isn't decided in the arena.
Tomorrow, all you need to do
is step into the arena.
Everything outside it
will be taken care of.
Do you have any rooms left?
Sorry.
We're closed for the night.
Now I get it.
Not one inn in the Capital
will take half-monsters.
Forget it.
We'll make do in an alley tonight.
Miss, Misters.
The people of the Lower City
may not know how to treat guests,
(Meiniang)
but I do.
Why not come to my Flower Boat Row
(Meiniang)
and stay the night?
(Flower Boat Row)
The Rouge River winds
around the Lower City.
Along its banks lies Flower Boat Row.
All seventy-two flower boats
belong to me.
Dad, aren't they half-monsters?
Why do they look just like us?
Once the lights go out
and the shops close,
their monster faces will show.
So don't wander off.
With the gods watching over us,
those monsters and ghouls
won't dare come near.
Okay.
What you three did was impressive.
I've always had a soft spot for heroes.
Flower Boat Row may not be fancy,
but we'll take good care of you.
A-Two, guests arriving!
(Help! Help!)
(I don't want to go back!)
(Grab her!)
(Help!)
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Yan,
I remember the Chief saying
you'd been to the Capital before.
That was many years ago.
I barely remember it.
Mr. Lu.
Hope I'm not disturbing you.
I warmed some wine for you.
It'll take the chill off.
Thanks.
Nights are cold.
Have some warm wine.
It'll warm you up.
Confident about tomorrow?
The Qi Sect has stood
for a hundred years.
Are you here to talk me
into backing down?
I'm only worried about you.
Young Master Qi has the Thunder field
on his side.
You only have Headwind.
This fight
won't be easy.
Then do you have a way
to help me turn things around
in the arena?
I don't know much about fighting
in the arena.
But what happens outside it?
That I understand.
I'm a businesswoman.
You entered the Ascension Trials
just to save your sister, didn't you?
I can help you.
How?
I have people in the Ministry of Rites.
I can send a girl from Flower Boat Row
in her place
and have your sister returned
to you unharmed.
How much
for this job?
In the Capital,
human life
is worthless.
My business needs
the Qi family's protection.
I want you
to lose to the Qi family
within one incense stick.
You work for the Qi family?
I work for whoever pays.
You're still young.
You haven't learned yet.
If you want to change your fate,
there's something sharper
than your blade.
Money.
In the Ascension Trials,
three arenas fight at once.
Winners may cross over
to aid their teammates.
Once the fighting begins,
blades show no mercy.
Life or death, there are no guarantees.
Begin!
Get him! Get him!
This is the Qi Sect's mystic artifact,
the Linglong Beads.
The Ling Bead becomes a mace,
and the Long Bead becomes armor.
(That's the Qi family's
Heavenly Thunder Armor.)
(With heavenly thunder protecting him,)
(that half-monster can't even
get close.)
Young Master Qi is
using the Thunder field
to amplify his heavenly thunder.
Without the Thunder field,
no matter how powerful
the Linglong Beads are,
they couldn't unleash their full power.
My son,
scared?
Today,
I'll show you the true power
of heavenly thunder!
And I thought you had some backbone.
Turns out you're just cheap trash
who can be bought.
Draw your blade!
Too scared to move?
I want you
to lose to the Qi family
within one incense stick.
Why one incense stick?
The arena is charged
with heavenly thunder
for one incense stick.
Once the incense burns out,
the arena's element resets.
Before the next charge begins,
there's a brief opening.
(Time is up.)
(This is my only chance
to turn the fight around.)
Is that all you've got?
Didn't eat enough today?
I will make it quick for you.
(Young Master Qi has the Thunder field
on his side.)
(You only have Headwind.)
(Each arena has two aspects,
each with its strengths and counters.)
(Mountain blocks the path of wind
and cloud.)
(Without flowing clouds,
thunder cannot rise.)
The arena flipped!
Grandson.
It's the Mountain field now!
Mountain counters Thunder!
Crap!
Well, well.
No sleeping in the arena.
What?
Not playing Daddy anymore?
You...
Didn't you make a deal with Meiniang?
I had to agree.
How else would I know
the arena's element resets?
And without the reset,
how could I turn the fight around?
You...
Shameless!
You broke your word!
You're the one who broke your word.
Ahai held out for half an incense stick.
Did you open the gate?
And the crystals you owed him?
Did you pay?
To hell with you!
I surrender! I surrender!
Listen up.
I'll ask you one question.
Answer correctly,
and I'll spare your sorry life.
Are sesame cakes sweet?
What are you talking about?
(He'd definitely stand up for us)
(and fight for justice.)
The Challenger wins!
Defender's all equipment
now belongs to
the victorious Challenger!
He's dead!
Fiend! She's a fiend!
Fiend!
Fiend is here!
A half-monster killed someone!
They've brought their killing
into the Lower City!
Gods above!
Drive them out!
Drive them out of the Capital!
I thought
you'd agreed to Meiniang's deal
last night.
Drive them out of the Capital!
(Money.)
I won't trade someone else's life
for my sister's.
Let me tell you a story.
Once, there was a little girl named Jiu.
She once went to Yuyou Village.
Jiu was from the Capital.
Her parents were merchants.
Their business failed,
leaving them deep in debt.
Meiniang brought her to Flower Boat Row.
It became
the darkest time of her life.
♪Reaching out again and again♪
Later,
Meiniang sent Jiu to Yuyou Village,
to take another girl's place
as an offering to the gods.
♪You speak without a sound♪
Outsiders all believed
Yuyou Village was home to the gods.
But in truth,
it was nothing but a playground
for the guardian gods.
To escape,
Jiu jumped from Mount Buzhou.
She fell into a pool
and was tainted by monster aura.
Later,
the Chief of Redtail saved her.
♪I long for impermanence♪
From that day on,
the girl named Jiu was gone.
And Redtail
gained a new escort.
♪Fate comes to rest♪
All these years, I've run escorts,
pretending none of it ever happened.
♪One stroke, heaven's time♪
Until one day,
I met someone.
(I'm going to smash the Eye of Heaven)
(to save my sister.)
That's when I realized
some things should never be forgotten,
much less forgiven.
♪Not its opposite♪
♪If we are steeped♪
♪In the amniotic waters of the world♪
Come on.
We're going back to Flower Boat Row.
♪Why should we hold on♪
♪You are far away♪
♪Lightning falls before you♪
Together,
we're making one escort run.
And on this run,
♪The tears she shed,
Have drowned our eyes♪
I'll protect you.
♪Nothing was ever there♪
♪Why should we hold on♪
♪I long for impermanence♪
♪The square and circle become poetry♪
♪Life and death, weariness♪
♪Fate comes to rest♪
♪One stroke, barren land♪
♪One stroke, heaven's time♪
(Help! Help!)
(Somebody help me!)
♪A lifetime has already passed♪
(Get off me! Help!)
Let her go!
- Who are you?
♪Life is the lover of death
Not its opposite♪
(Jiu)
♪In the amniotic waters of the world♪
♪Nothing was ever there♪
What do you want?
Jewelry?
Gold? Silver? Valuables?
I'll give you whatever you want.
♪If the ground is split open♪
♪A face is revealed♪
♪The tears she shed♪
♪Have drowned our eyes♪
You?
♪Why should we hold on♪
Do you remember Jiu?
This escort run
is taking Jiu
home.
Thank you!
- Careful.
- Thank you!
- Thank you for saving us!
- Easy now.
Miss.
Did you come to save me too?
♪Life and death, weariness♪
♪Fate comes to rest♪
♪One stroke, barren land♪
Let's go.
♪One stroke, heaven's time♪
♪No one was ever there♪
♪A lifetime has already passed♪
♪Summer is noon♪
♪And winter is the long night♪
♪Life is the lover of death♪
=Episode 6=
(Save yourself in a world of suffering.)
♪If we are steeped♪
♪In the amniotic waters of the world♪
♪Nothing was ever there♪
♪Why should we hold on♪
♪You are far away♪
♪Lightning falls before you♪
♪If the ground is split open♪
♪A face is revealed♪
♪The tears she shed♪
♪Have drowned our eyes♪
♪Nothing was ever there♪
♪Why should we hold on♪